<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cookbook version="1">
    <recipe>
        <title>Meatballs</title>
        <imagepath>
            ../../resources/images/meatballs.jpg
        </imagepath>
        <description>
            Makes about 30 delicious meatballs.
        </description>
        <ingredient>
            <li>1 pound beef</li>
            <li>1/2 cup milk</li>
            <li>1/2 cup fine bread crumbs</li>
            <li>1 egg</li>
            <li>1/2 cup finely chopped onion</li>
            <li>1/2 cup Parmesan cheese</li>
            <li>1 clove garlic</li>
            <li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
            <li>lots of black pepper</li>
        </ingredient>
        <recipetext>
            <li>
                Combine the milk and bread crumbs: 
                Pour the milk over the bread crumbs in a small bowl and set aside while preparing the rest of the meatball mix. 
                The bread crumbs will absorb the milk and become soggy.
            </li>
            <li>
                Whisk the egg, salt, pepper, Parmesan, and parsley: 
                Whisk the egg in a large bowl until blended. 
                Whisk in the salt and a generous quantity of black pepper, then whisk in the Parmesan and parsley.
            </li>
            <li>
                Combine the egg and ground meat: Add the meat to the egg mixture. 
                Use your hands to thoroughly mix the egg into the ground meat.
            </li>
            <li>
                Add the onions and soaked bread crumbs: Add the onions, garlic, and soaked bread crumbs to the meat. 
                Mix them thoroughly into the meat with your fingers. 
                Try not to overwork the meat; pinch the meat between your fingers rather than kneading it.
            </li>
            <li>
                Form the meat into meat balls: 
                Pinch off a piece of the meat mixture and gently roll between your hands to form 1 1/2-inch meatballs. 
                Continue shaping until all the meat is used.
            </li>
            <li> 
                Arrange the meatballs spaced slightly apart on a baking sheet. 
                Cook under the broiler for 20 to 25 minutes or bake at 400°F for 25 to 30 minutes. 
                (Watch closely if cooking meatballs made with lean meat.) 
                The meatballs are done when cooked through and the outside is browned, 
                and when they register 165°F in the middle on an instant read thermometer. 
                Serve immediately.
            </li>
        </recipetext>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Pancakes</title>
        <imagepath>
            ../../resources/images/pancakes.jpg
        </imagepath>
        <description>
            Makes about 12 delicious pancakes.
        </description>
        <ingredient>
            <li>1 1/4 cup milk</li>
            <li>3 table spoons butter, melted</li>
            <li>1 egg</li>
            <li>1 cup all-purpose flour</li>
            <li>2 table spoons sugar</li>
            <li>2 1/2 tea spoons baking powder</li>
            <li>1/2 tea spoon salt</li>
        </ingredient>
        <recipetext>
            <li>
                In large bowl, whisk flour, sugar, baking powder and salt. 
                Add milk, butter and egg; stir until flour is moistened.
            </li>
            <li>
                Heat 12-inch nonstick skillet or griddle over medium heat until drop of water sizzles; 
                brush lightly with oil. 
                In batches, scoop batter by scant 1/4-cupfuls into skillet, spreading to 3 1/2 inches each. 
                Cook 2 to 3 minutes or until bubbly and edges are dry. 
                With wide spatula, turn; cook 2 minutes more or until golden. 
                Transfer to platter or keep warm on a cookie sheet in 225°F oven.
            </li>
            <li>
                Repeat with remaining batter, brushing griddle with more oil if necessary.
            </li>
        </recipetext>
    </recipe>
</cookbook>